We will begin this exercise with the 3 -to -1 method.
Find a comfortable position.
Close your eyes.
Take a deep breath.
And while exhaling, mentally repeat and visualize the number 3,
three times.
To help you relax physically at level 3, I'm going to direct
your attention to different parts of your body.
Relax your scalp.
Relax your forehead. head.
Relax your eyes and the tissue surrounding your eyes.
give yourself a slight smile and relax the muscles of your face
relax your throat
Relax your shoulders, arms and hands. ends.
Take a deep breath and while exhaling relax your chest
externally and internally.
Take another deep breath, and while exhaling, mentally relax
your abdominal area, externally and internally.
Relax your thighs.
Relax your knees. knees.
Relax your calves.
Relax your feet.
you are now at a deeper healthier level of mind deeper than
before this is your physical relaxation level three whenever you
mentally repeat and visualize the number three
your body will relax as completely as you are now and more
so every time you practice
to enter mental relaxation level to take a deep breath and while
exhaling mentally repeat and visualize the number two three
times and you are at level two a deeper level than and
3.
Level 2 is for mental relaxation, where noises will not distract
you.
Instead, noises will help you to relax mentally more and more.
To improve mental relaxation at level two practice visualizing
tranquil and passive scenes do that now
take another deep breath and while exhaling mentally repeat and
visualize
number one, three times.
You are now at level one,
a deeper, healthier level of mind.
To help you enter a deeper, healthier level of mind, I'm going
to count from 10 to 1 on each descending number you will
feel yourself going deeper and you will enter a deeper healthier
level of mind 10 9 feel going going deeper, 8, 7, 6,
deeper and deeper, 5, 4, 3, deeper and deeper, 2, 1, you
are now at a deeper healthier level of mind deeper than before
it is a wonderful feeling to be deeply relaxed a very healthy
state of being effective sensory projection statements for
success I am now able to attune my intelligence by developing my
sensing faculties and to experience myself as any point place
level or depth so as to be aware of any actions taking
place
i am able to function in non -locality regarding time and space
I am aware that intelligence can exist at all levels and depths
in the universe and therefore I can attune to all information I
am now able to use my sensing faculties and to experience myself
as any matter kingdom,
mineral, plant,
animal and human if this is what I desire to do.
I am now able to detect abnormalities whenever such
abnormalities exist
within any kingdom, any level and any depth.
I am now able to apply corrective measures and to bring back
to normalcy any abnormality found within any kingdom any level
and any depth Quantum energy is available at any level to be
acted upon to create through the subjective and objective
dimensions
we will now program effective sensory projection for your
success we will program information through the use of mental
projection we will establish subjective points of reference at
the imaginative dimension the subjective dimension at different
levels and depths in a moment i'm going to count from one
to three and cause a sound with my fingers at that time
you will imagine yourself to be standing about 30 feet in front
of your home
you will study the outer appearance of your home scanning the
scene you will start at the top left of the scene and
go from left to right just as you do when reading a
page of a book.
You will then go to the left side of the scene again
but a little lower than before and again go from left to
right.
You will continue going a little lower each time until you reach
the ground level.
I will now count from one to three and cause a sound
with my fingers so that you may imagine projecting yourself to
the front of your home one two three project yourself mentally
to the front of your home standing about 30 feet from it
begin scanning the scene at the upper left hand corner going
slowly from left to right lower and lower each time until you
reach the ground level you will go slowly and stop to study
anything that attracts your intelligence while scanning such as
the roof windows window frames doors study Study anything that
attracts you.
At any given moment, should something attract your attention,
you may experience yourself as that object, point, or place.
Begin by studying the roof of your home.
What material is it made of?
what color is it experience yourself ask the roof continue
studying everything that attracts you until you reach the ground
level concentrate on colors take your time
study colors
Take your time.
Concentrate on colors.
Scan the ground level.
Now focus your attention on the front door and concentrate on
the doorknob or handle.
Mentally move close to the door.
Close enough to touch the door handle.
expect the door to appear to increase in size as you get
closer mentally touch the doorknob or handle open the door
mentally enter your home closing the door behind you
mentally walk toward your living room once you have entered your
living room stand at the center facing the south wall you have
been here before you have been here during daylight hours you
have been here during nighttime with the lights turned on and
the lights turned off
I'm going to count from 1 to 3 at the count of
3 it will be daytime 1 2 3 it is now daytime
you are standing at the center of your living room facing the
south wall you have been here before
you know how much light enters this room you know how much
light enters this room during the day and you recognize what is
in front of you what is behind you you You know what
is to your left and what is to your right.
At the count of three, we will change the scene to nighttime
with the house lights turned on. One, two, three.
The scene has changed to nighttime,
and you are still standing in the middle of the living room
facing the south wall.
you have been here before and you know what is in front
of you what is behind you what is to your left and
what is to your right at the count of three the lights
will go out one two three the lights are out and you
are standing in darkness facing the south wall although the
living room looks dark you still know what's in front of you
what is behind you
what is to your left and what is to your right
at this time concentrate on the wall before you the south wall
you can sense it being a certain distance away and you know
what is on this wall you also know the color of this
wall
use your memory your knowing your sensing to make a study of
the south wall scan this wall as you did the front of
your home begin by scanning the upper left corner and going from
left to right a little lower each time until you reach the
floor level study everything that attracts you experience
yourself as anything that attracts you
pictures curtains and furniture especially concentrate on
objects that contain color.
Take your time.
Take your time. Study colors.
Concentrate on colors.
Take your time.
now mentally walk toward the south wall and stand close enough
to touch it at the count of three you will objectively raise
your hand to touch the south wall one two three
objectively stretch out your arm raise your hand and with the
palm of your hand touch the wall
use your imagination to sense the wall as being smooth or rough
as cool, or warm.
Whatever you perceive with your imagination at this dimension,
you can use as a point of reference in the future.
At the count of three, you will imagine projecting yourself
subjectively within the wall. One, two, three.
You are now within the wall. You may return your hand to
rest on your lap.
At this time, we will conduct four tests subjectively.
First we will test for light, intensity and color.
Our second test is for temperature.
The third test is for odor.
and the fourth for solidity of material by reflected sound at
the count of three we will test for light its intensity in
color one two three subjectively test for light intensity in
color how much light do you sense what color do you sense
whatever you perceive with your imagination at this dimension
you can use as a point of reference in the future at
the count of three test for temperature one two three
subjectively test for temperature is there a difference in
temperature between the inside and the outside side of the wall
whatever you perceive with your imagination at this dimension
you can use as a point of reference in the future at
the count of three test Test for odor. One, two, three.
Test for odor.
Is there a difference in odor between the inside and the outside
of the wall?
Whatever you perceive with your imagination at this dimension,
you can use as a point of reference in the future at
the count of three tests for solidity of material by knocking on
the inside of the wall one two three objectively form a fist
and knock on the inside of the wall objectively go through the
motions as you do when you knock on a door
what kind of sound would you expect to hear reflected back to
you how solid would you judge the material to be whatever you
perceive with your imagination at this dimension you can use as
a point of reference in the future at the count of three
you will come out of the wall and be just a few
inches away from it one two three you are now out of
the wall just a few inches away now at the count of
three you will be at arm's length one two three you are
now at arm's length sense the distance at the count of three
you will be at the center of your living room facing the
south wall one two
You are now at the center of your living room, facing the
south wall.
You know the color of your living room wall.
At the count of three, the color of the wall will change
to black.
One, two, three.
The color of the wall is now black.
you can get a true black color by imagining a painter with
a can of paint and the brush in his hand painting the
wall black and about to finish painting it the south wall is
now all black at the count of three it will be red
one two three it is now red to get a true red
color again imagine the painter about to finish painting it red
at the count of three the wall will be green one two
three the wall is now green imagine it green
at the count of three the wall will be blue one two
three the wall is now blue imagine it blue
at the count of three the wall will be violet one two
three the wall is now violet imagine it violet we will change
the color back to blue back to green
back to red
and back to black.
We will now mentally examine a chair, selecting any chair we
wish.
Mentally, push it against the black wall. From your position in
the center of the living room, facing the south wall mentally
lift the chair about 20 degrees above the horizontal plane of
sight in the area of your mental screen
we will examine the chair studying its material
the upholstery if it is upholstered and how it is attached to
the chair and the color of the chair concentrate on colors now
mentally turn the chair toward the left now away from you now
toward the right now facing you whatever you perceive with your
imagination at this dimension you can use as a point of of
reference in the future at the count of three the color of
the wall will change to its actual color one two three the
wall is now its actual color again study the chair how does
it stand out against this background whatever you perceive with
your imagination you can use as a point of reference in the
future at the count of three the color of the wall will
change to red one two three the wall is now red study
the chair how does it stand out against a red background
whatever you perceive with your imagination you can use as a
point of reference in the future at the count of three the
color of the wall will change to green one two three the
wall is now green study the chair how How does it stand
out against a green background?
Whatever you perceive with your imagination at this dimension,
you can use as a point of reference in the future.
At the count of three, the color of the wall will change
to blue.
One, two, three.
The wall is now blue.
study the chair how does it stand out against a blue background
whatever you perceive with your imagination at this dimension
you can use as a point of reference in the future the
color of the wall will now change back to green
back to red back to the natural color back to black at
the count of three the chair will disappear from the scene one
two three the chair has disappeared from the scene the wall is
now black at the count of three we will mentally bring into
the scene a watermelon it will be up against the wall at
the height where we had the chair one two three study this
watermelon use your knowing your memory your sensing above all
use your imagination to study the watermelon
observe how the green stands out against the black background at
the count of three the watermelon will be cut in half one
two three the watermelon is now cut in half
and you can visualize how the red portion of the watermelon
lined with black seeds stands out against the white inner rind
and the green of the outside as you mentally bring the two
halves closely toward you notice how they appear to increase in
size examine the various colors the red the white the black and
the green from only a few inches away
now imagine the odor and the taste of watermelon
Whatever you perceive with your imagination at this dimension,
you can use as a point of reference in the future.
At the count of three, the watermelon will be near the wall,
one, two, three. the watermelon is now near the wall at the
count of three the two halves will come together one two three
now at the count of three the watermelon will disappear from the
scene 1 2 3 the watermelon has disappeared from the scene at
the count of 3 a lemon will appear at the same level
near the wall 1 2 3 a lemon appears in a fluorescent
yellow yellow color that stands out against the black wall.
Bring the lemon closer to you noticing how it appears to
increase in size as it approaches.
stop the approaching lemon when it's only a few inches away and
examine its color now imagine the odor and taste of a lemon
whatever you perceive with your imagination at this dimension
you can use as a point of reference in the future at
the count of three the lemon will be near the wall one
two three the lemon is now near the wall a little higher
than the horizontal level of sight
at the count of three the lemon will disappear from the scene
one two three
The lemon has disappeared from the scene.
At the count of three, an orange will appear. One, two, three.
An orange has appeared on the scene.
Observe the color at a distance.
Now bring the orange closer.
Again, observe the color.
Now imagine the odor and taste of an orange.
How is it different than a lemon and a watermelon?
Whatever you perceive with your imagination at this dimension,
you can use as a point of reference in the future.
at the count of three the orange will be near the wall
one two three the orange is now near the wall at the
count of three the orange will disappear from the scene one two
three the orange has disappeared from the scene at the count of
three three bananas will appear one two three three bananas have
appeared study the color from far and near
Now, imagine the odor and taste of bananas.
How is the odor and taste of bananas different than that of
the orange, the lemon, and the watermelon? melon.
Whatever you perceive with your imagination at this dimension
you can use as a point of reference in the future.
At the count of three the bananas will be near the wall
one two three now at the count of three the bananas will
disappear from the scene one two three the bananas have
disappeared from the scene at the count of three three carrots
will appear one two three three carrots have appeared study the
color from far and near now imagine the odor and taste of
carrots
How are the carrots different compared to the bananas, the
orange, the lemon and the watermelon?
Whatever you perceive with your imagination at this dimension,
you can use as a point of reference in the future.
at the count of three the carrots will be near the wall
one two three now at the count of three the carrots will
disappear from the scene one two three the carrots have
disappeared from the scene
at the count of three a fresh and crisp head of lettuce
will appear one two three a head of lettuce has appeared study
the color from far now bring it closer and study the color
from a distance of about 12 inches whatever you perceive with
your imagination at this dimension
you can use as a point of reference in the future at
the count of three the head of lettuce will be near the
wall one two three now at the count of three the head
of lettuce will disappear from the scene one two three the head
of lettuce has disappeared from the scene whatever you perceive
with your imagination you can use as points of reference in the
future it is now an accomplished fact that subjective points of
reference have been established at the imaginative dimension at
the subjective dimension at different levels and different
depths to function at these levels and to use these points of
reference all you need is to have a sincere desire to solve
problems your mind will automatically seek out these points of
reference that you can use in problem -solving every time you
function at these levels of the mind and at these points of
reference you will receive beneficial effects physically and
mentally
you may use these levels of the mind in these points of
reference to help yourself to help your loved ones and to help
any human being who needs help physically and mentally you will
always use these levels of the mind in these points of reference
in a constructive creative manner for all that is good honest
pure clean and positive and this is so you will continue to
strive to take part in constructive and creative activities to
make this a better world to live in so that when you
move on you shall have left behind a better world for those
who follow you You will consider the whole of humanity,
depending on their ages, as fathers or mothers, brothers or
sisters, sons or daughters.
You are a superior human being. You have greater understanding,
compassion, and patience with others.
In a moment, I'm going to count from one to five and
cause a sound with my fingers. At that moment, you will open
your eyes, be wide awake, feeling fine and in perfect health,
feeling better than before.
1, 2, coming out slowly now, 3.
At the count of 5, you will open your eyes, be wide
awake, feeling fine and in perfect health, feeling better than
before. Four, four, five. Eyes open, wide awake, feeling fine
and in perfect health, feeling better than before.
To guarantee success with your Silva techniques, we recommend
that you take the Silva seminars live. For more information over
course schedules and locations, log on to silvamethod .com or
call 1 -800 -545 -6463 within the continental United States or
956 -722 -6391.